SMIT SANTOSH SHEWALE

(213) 275-9123 | smitshewale@gmail.com | GitHub | Behance | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

UX Designer and Product Builder with a strong foundation in user-centered design, design systems, and research-driven decision-making. Experience spans academic research, internal university products, and cofounding an NGO-focused event app. Comfortable leading client discussions, conducting usability testing, and iterating high-fidelity prototypes in Figma.

EDUCATION

University of Southern California (USC)

Los Angeles, CA

Master of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2022-May 2024

Relevant Coursework: Human Computer Interaction, Mobile and Web Development, Data Structures, Game Development

SKILLS

Design: Interaction design for iOS, Android, and Web, Information architecture, Creation of Design Systems, Creative writing, Content strategizing, Cognitive Psychology, Prototyping, WCAG, Web accessibility, Universal design for learning (UDL). **Research**: Competitive Analysis, Usability testing, User interviews, Contextual Inquiry, Ethnographic research, Personas, User Journeys, Affinity mapping, Heuristic evaluation, Task flows development, Data visualization.

Tools: Figma (3+ years), ReactJs, Wordpress, Framer, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, Bootstrap, ServiceNow, Salesforce marketing cloud.

EXPERIENCE

UX Research Assistant – Adaptive Computing Experiences Lab USC

May 2024-July 2024

- Conducted in-depth research on software developers' interactions with Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT, Claude, and GitHub Copilot, to identify cognitive biases and behavioral patterns in software development workflows
- Synthesized qualitative data from interviews and recorded coding sessions, delivering actionable insights to analyze the usability and effectiveness of LLMs in software development workflows
- Developed research-based recommendations for improving LLM-assisted coding experiences, focusing on reducing friction, and enhancing developer trust in AI-generated suggestions

Web Designer and Developer - Engineering in Society Program USC

Jan 2024-May 2024

- Redesigned key website interfaces based on user flow analysis and usability testing, improving session duration by 12%
- Launched UX/UI experiments to test interface enhancements (e.g., modals, carousels, hover effects), contributing to a 10% drop in bounce rate and improved navigation clarity
- Collaborated cross-functionally with product and dev teams to implement responsive layouts and performance improvements, reducing page load time by 20% and driving higher user engagement across devices

Front End Engineer – Tvishtryon Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Oct 2021-Aug 2022

- Designed and developed an interactive and responsive website and an admin dashboard using Figma, React, TypeScript and Redux, enabling real-time data monitoring and configuration for internal users
- Led collaborative design workshops with stakeholders to gather insights and align on design objectives
- Conducted usability testing and A/B experimentation, contributing to a 15% increase in task success rates across the app

UX PROJECTS

MyViterbi Redesign (Demo)

- Led a full UX audit and redesign of the MyViterbi portal, reducing average task time by 42% and user errors by 100%, and achieving a 93% satisfaction rate through extensive testing and iteration
- Conducted user research, interviews, and usability inquiries to identify pain points across mobile and web workflows
- Designed interactive interfaces in Figma, focusing on streamlining activation paths and improving usability for first-time users

Rotaract (NGO) And You Mobile Application (Demo)

- Cofounded and led UX for an NGO-focused event management app, conducting branding sessions with partners to align on organizational goals and design direction.
- Spearheaded end-to-end UI/UX design in Figma, incorporating user interviews and usability testing with club members, leading to iterative design of 21 app screens in Figma
- Achieved an 83% user satisfaction rate during prototype testing, showing clear improvement in retention and user confidence

LEADERSHIP AND INVOLVEMENT

Creatives Director - Rotaract Club Of Thane North End (Non-profit organization)

India, Jul 2020-Jun 2021

- Nominated for 'Best Creatives Director' award for impactful leadership and innovative content strategy
- Collaborated with Arana Foundation to launch a fundraising campaign, successfully supporting the education of 25+ underprivileged children
- Directed a design team of to curate appealing digital content, marketing ideas and handled social media accounts